RICHARD PHILIPOSE

(770) 570-6929 • philipose.richard@gmail.com • https://www.linkedin.com/in/richard-phillips-b48716ba/https://github.com/richardatl5

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Business Intelligence/Data Analyst with 1 year of experience analyzing federal sales trends and developing business intelligence reports for sales executive team. Looking to enter a competitive, growth-oriented company to utilize my process-oriented data analytical skills.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages	Python, JavaScript
Data Visualization	Tableau, D3.js, Matplotlib, R, Plotly, Seaborn
Databases	MySQL, PostreSQL (Postgres), MongoDB, SQLite
Front End Development	HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Geomapping, Framework – Flask, Django
Other tools	Excel, SharePoint, Web Framework - Flask, Django

EDUCATION

Georgia Institute of Technology
Data Science & Analytics Certification

Atlanta, Georgia

September 2020 - March 2021

Georgia State University

-- (D---'- List)

Atlanta, Georgia May 2018

Bachelor's in Interdisciplinary Studies: Health Informatics (Dean's List)

Overall GPA: 3.7/4.0

WORK EXPERIENCE

TalTeam Inc.

Washington, DC

Pre-Sales Data Analyst

March 2020 - Present

- Developed federal-agency specific business intelligence reports by working with the sales and federal
 capture team to identify appropriate data sources and extracted data for visualizations and reporting
 which increased contract wins by 40% year over year.
- Gathered requirements for each business team and created reports and communicated analysis and findings to the stakeholders.
- Created and maintained data visualizations that informed the sales team of key metrics and performance measures using data-storytelling to present that facts.
- Developed data-first initiative at TalTeam and created CMMI level 3 oriented data entry processes for the sales team to capture data for data-based decision-making capability at TalTeam.

Federal Capture Lead

Oct 2018 - Mar 2020

- Responsible for analyzing government contracting data and initiatives to create a strategic plan to win federal technology contracts.
- Worked with teams in business development, capture and proposal development for agencies such as IRS, FDIC, Library of Congress, CDC, and Health & Human Services for IT consulting-based contracts with combined contract value of over \$6 million dollars.

PROJECTS

FIFA Interactive Dashboard

- Developed an interactive live dashboard from a dataset of over 100,000 rows using python, javascript, front-end tools, flask and Cloud (AWS & Heroku).
- Extracted and cleaned the data with pandas and loaded the data to a SQLite database to have the data available via API and created website with HTML, CSS & Bootstrap and utilized Flask server to server the dashboard and the data from the API.
- Created visualizations using Plotly, D3.js, Vue.js, Charts.js and leaflet.js for geo-mapping.

Sales Analytics Dashboard (Tableau)

• Government contract spending from usaspending.gov, beta.sam.gov API to analyze how small business can target appropriate agencies.